### **CONTACT ME**

#### **Personal info**

Mahowino@gmail.com

+254769694842

Nairobi, Kenya

https://github.com/mahowino

www.linkedin.com/in/mahalonowino

## **EXPERTISE / SKILLS**

### **Front-end**

React Angular Jetpack compose

#### **Backend**

Java spring Express.js

## <u>DevOps</u>

Docker Git Linux basic commands

#### <u>Databases</u>

PostgreSQL Firebase

## <u>Package Managers</u>

Package managers Node and Pip

#### **PROJECTS**

## Door Drop (Android App)

An android app used for delivery of goods to your doorstep.

Link https://bit.ly/44s64Xk

Smart patrol (Android App)

A patrolling security software that ensures that guards are able to digitally work their shifts through scanning QR codes at checkpoints

Link https://bit.ly/41ai4dT

# Poolr and Poolr Driver (Android App)

This is an Android App that is used to facilitate carpooling.

GitHub linkhttps://bit.ly/40R8XPp https://bit.ly/435xCBv

#### Mahallon Owino

## Full Stack engineer | Machine learning engineer

I am a recent graduate of Computer Science and a largely self-taught full-stack developer who has experience implementing solutions using, Java Spring framework, Angular, Typescript, React, JavaScript and rest APIs among others. I am highly analytical and an effective problem-solver, who thrives in a collaborative atmosphere to deliver quality results.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Feb 2022 - Present

#### M-Vitu

A Goods delivery startup I started to offer a way to deliver local goods to users more effectively

March 2023 - Present

#### **Freelance**

Carried out private lessons in python to a beginner programmer.

Dec 2022-Feb 2023

#### Soma

A startup that allows you to trade skills with others using credits

## **Full Stack Developer**

- 1.Orchestrated end-to-end project management, delivering outcomes on a two week sprint schedule, and ensuring client satisfaction
- 2.Refactored the code base to improve performance which reduced load time from 5 seconds to 3 seconds.
- 3.Designed the system including Figma prototypes, class diagrams and Database diagrams using drawer.io

**Python Personal Tutor** 

- 1.Run timely two hour sessions on the basics of python and improved the students skill by 30% through tests
- 2.Created SSH keys and linked to GitHub while teaching git commands to the student
- 3.Led the student in creating his first python calculator which improved his python knowledge by 10% through tests

**Backend Java Developer** 

- 1.Containerised the backend using a docker file to allow for seamless deployment in the production pipeline to allow seamless deployment
- 2.Implemented a Java spring CRUD backend with Spring security using JWT Tokens which increased the backend security two fold
- 3.Tested API endpoints using postman and Curl which ensured API performance increased

March 2020 – March 2022

#### **Poolr Ridesharing**

A carpooling startup I started to give community carpools in a secure environment to lower fuel cost

1 2022 Co-Founder and CTO

- 1.Management of developer team of Backend (Java spring) and front-end (Kotlin) developers in an agile environment using Jira and Trello with 3 week sprints.
- 2.Implemented use of git to collaborate with developers which improved code management making sprints shorter by two weeks.
- 3.Designing of database diagrams and implementation of serverless Firebase database.

## **EDUCATION**

August 2017 - Dec 2022

**Kenyatta University** 

# Bachelor of Science Computer Science

Gained extensive knowledge in Java, by collaborating with a fellow student to build two android apps project which both projects got an A

Aug 2022 - Nov 2022

**Kenyatta University** 

Data Science And Machine Learning Certification

Trained various models, including churn predictor and bike regression algorithms

March 2018 - Aug 2018 E-mobilis

## **Android Development Certificate**

Built an e-commerce app and personal website which got recognition as part of the top 10 best projects